# Michał Wadowski

## Senior Java Developer

## Contact

**Address** 

Warsaw, Poland

**Phone** 

+48 796 334 459

E-mail

wadosm@gmail.com

Github

https://github.com/Michal-Wadowski

## **Experience and knowledge**

Programming languages / technologies

Java: JUnit/Mockito, Lombok, Hibernate

Spring: Boot, Security, JPA, Kafka Javasript: ES6, JSX, ReactJS, Redux

Python: DataFrame, Numpy

**Databases** 

PostgreSQL/pgSQL, MongoDB,

Liquibase

Other tools / technologies

Kubernetes, AWS, Azure, Docker compose, Maven, GIT, Jenkins

**Good practices** 

TDD, DDD, Clean architecture, software

design patterns

IDE

IntelliJ IDEA

**Operating systems** 

Linux, Windows

Software Development Model

SCRUM

Languages and technologies in past

Android in Kotlin

C, C++

I'm a software development passionate with over 14 years of experience in various technologies and languages. I have been working in Java oriented projects for 5 years mostly using Spring Boot in combination with AWS / Azure, Kubernetes, Kafka, PostgreSQL, MongoDB. I value clean code, TDD and other good programming practices.

## **Professional experience**

HSBC Service Delivery (Polska) Sp. z o.o.

(Polska) Sp. z o.o.

/ Mindbox S.A. 08.2022 - 12.2024 Senior Java Developer

Developing "Strategic Financial Planning" - internal business application written in **Java 8 - 21** with **Spring Boot** in microservices architecture.

Technologies used: JUnit & Mockito, Java Reactor,

Lombok, PostgreSQL & Oracle + Liquibase

Kubernetes with AWS, Jenkins and ReactJS were

used in project as well

Orange Polska S.A.

02.2022 - 07.2022

Java Developer with

Developing microservices for streaming platform

using Kafka, MongoDB and Java Reactor

Orange Polska S.A.

02.2021 - 07.2022

Java Developer

Developing Eclipse Leshan library

https://www.eclipse.org/leshan in Java for IoT communication protocol (Lightweight M2M).

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

08.2020 - 07.2022

Developing research application ThingIn The City using **Spring Boot** and **PostgreSQL** technologies.

Orange Polska S.A.

**Android Developer** 

03.2020 - 01.2021

Developing mobile application for technicians

using Live Objects platform

https://liveobjects.orange-business.com with Android Studio in Java and Kotlin languages.

As a development model was used SCRUM

framework.

Awans Sp. z o. o.

**Full-stack Developer** 

06.2014 - 02.2020

Developing  $\underline{\text{https://awanser.pl}}$  business platform

using technologies:

Frontend: ReactJS with Redux and Ecmascript 6,

CSS, LESS and SCSS

Backend: PHP and CakePHP framework,
PostgreSQL database system, Azure

#### Courses

Creating  $\mu$ Services using Spring Cloud and Docker

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

**Spring Framework II** 

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Pragmatic refactoring using DDD techniques

https://bottega.com.pl

Clean Code in Java

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Test-Driven Development in practice https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

## **Useful characteristics**

Writing good quality code Experienced in working with legacy systems

IT technologies quick learner Teamwork skills

Independence and responsibility

## Languages

Polish

Native

**English** 

B2

### **Passions & hobbies**

Programming microcontrollers and developing electronic circuits Building and training artificial neural networks

Developing applications and devices for own needs

Astronomy, quantum physics and science in general

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. Java Developer

**01.2013 - 05.2014** Developing integration layer with ePUAP system in

Java and PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. Software Developer

10.2011 - 12.2012 Developing of business application in **Delphi** and

PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL

iDelfi Polska Sp. z o. o. Full-stack Developer

**11.2009 - 12.2010** Developing internet application for HACCP

management in technologies: Ruby on Rails,

Javascript, jQuery, MySQL

## **Training**

March 2022 Professional Scrum Developer

I (PSD I)

**Education** 

2009 - 2011 University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn

Field of study: Computer science

M. Sc.

2005 - 2008 University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn

Field of study: Computer systems

Undergraduate course